

NICK RUSLAN

Glen Iris, VIC 3146 | 0435184331 |

nasirruslan91@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Talented medical scientist with 2 years of experience analyzing specimens and delivering speedy results to propel health outcomes for patients. Meticulous when completing activities such as documenting test findings, maintaining test equipment and driving quality control. Prompt and professional when communicating with clinical staff to deliver test results. I am currently located in Victoria, Australia seeking further opportunities. I am willing to move insterstate if the right opportunity arises.

SKILLS

- Maintenance & Repair
- Data Management
- Multitasking
- Computer and data analysis skills
- People skills
- Organizational skills
- Relationship building

- Quality assurance controls Sterilization techniques
- Specimen analysis
- Analytical thinking
- Troubleshooting
- Microscopy
- Working collaboratively
- Equipment testing and calibration

EXPERIENCE

03/2022 to 10/2022 PCR Lab Scientist

SafeWork Laboratories – Brisbane, Queensland

- Maintaining all appropriate accreditation
 - Taking directions and advice from the Laboratory Manager
 - Performing all testing assays and procedures necessary in compliance with relevant testing standards such as AS ISO 15189
 - Reporting and administrative requirements as agreed by the Laboratory
- Manager
- Maintaining customer satisfaction
- Responding to complaints as necessary
 - Ensuring adequate reagent stock is maintained and stores orders are dispatched within 48 hrs.
 - Assisting in work up/validation and verification of new tests/methods

02/2020 to 02/2022 Medical Technologist

Parkway Laboratories – Singapore

- Perform laboratory investigations in the following sections:
- Blood Bank
- Clinical Chemistry
- Haematology/Coagulation
- Immunoassay
- Microscopy (Urine, Stool, Fluids)
- Carry out quality control check on tests, calibrate laboratory analysers, verify reports and rectify any discrepancies or inconsistencies in test results;
- Assist in the servicing and maintenance of laboratory equipment
- Issue compatible blood products to patients from the blood bank as requested by doctors
- Conduct PCR analysis for Covid-19 samples in the clinical section using a variety of test procedures such as Resolute, Resolute 2.0, Perkin Elmer, Cobas

and Fortitude with little supervision by a senior staff

- Follows Laboratory policy for registration, billing, identification, processing, reporting, result retrieval and record/specimen keeping
- Checks the performance of all instruments and equipment in the Laboratory and to report any equipment which is not functioning properly
- Complies with all regulatory guidelines, participating in CAP proficiency testing programs and in hospital quality assurance programs

09/2019 to 04/2020 Desktop Engineer

Infinite Computer Solutions – Singapore

- Provide onsite support to users with good customer satisfaction for main and off-site:
- Service cases escalated by helpdesk, ensure service report forms are completed and update/close tickets on a timely manner as per ticker update/closure procedure;
- Troubleshoot any Level 1 & 2 problems with resolutions;
- Provide technical and operation support;
- Break/fix for patches, software distribution and preventive maintenance;

01/2014 to 01/2018 Assistant Manager

Langwarrin Newsagency - Victoria

- Daily managing of store, doing stock inventories and ordering
- Managing relationships and networks with clients and business partners
- Managing staff in running the business

06/2017 to 08/2017 Laboratory Assistant

Molecular and Medical Research, Deakin University – Australia

- Secured position from over 100 applicants through carefully prepared interviews, excellent academic performance and emails
- Led a team of students on a series of laboratory duties as well as assignments given by the head supervisor
- Performed PCR (polymerase chain reaction) techniques on certain genes of interest using PCR machines
- Cultivated and harvested cancer cell lines as preparation work for laboratory practical sessions
- Used an array of laboratory techniques such as electrophoresis and protein and gene detection such as Western and Southern blotting.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

01/2019 Postgraduate Diploma: Business Administration

Society of Business Practitioners (SBP) – Singapore, Singapore

01/2017 Bachelor of Biomedical Science: Cell and Molecular Biology **Deakin University** – Burwood, VIC

01/2009 Victorian Certificate of Examination

Mount Eliza Secondary College – Mount Eliza, VIC

INTERESTS

Active community member and regular volunteer for animal shelters and animal welfare organisations such as Animal Welfare League and AWARE.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Was part of the pioneer batch for Covid-19 PCR testing in Singapore under Parkway Laboratories. Was recognised by then Singapore Health Minister Dr. Lawrence Wong for efforts.

References can be provided upon request.